Guide to the Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection, 1896-1967, bulk 1911-1954 RL.11741
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Soviet-Western Relations, 1921-1959; 36 pamphlets
  - Western Attitudes to the USSR, 1921-1959
    Pamphlets which are considered neither radical nor anti-Communist, issued in the West and discussing attitudes and relations with the Soviet Union. One pamphlet was written by Richard M. Nixon in 1959.
    - The Soviet Russia Medical Relief Committee. Medical Relief Work in Soviet Russia, 1921 (Box 26)
    - Lyons, Eugene. Three Years of Russia Under Soviet Rule, 1931 (Box 26)
    - Greenwood, Arthur [comp.]. The Soviets' Fighting Forces, 1939 (Box 26)
    - Lamont, Corliss. Has Stalin a New Policy?, [1941?] [typescript of radio speech given in May, 1941] (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Oliveira Salazar, Antonio de. The West Faces Russia..., 1948 (Box 26)
    - Schuman, Frederick L. The Devil and Jimmy Byrnes..., 1948 (Box 26)
    - Friends of Fighters for Russian Freedom. How to Help Stalin Win the World: Who is the Enemy-- "Russia" or Communism? [1952] (Box 26)
    - Sargeant, Howland H. Communicating With the People Behind the Iron Curtain, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Nixon, Richard M. ...The Lesson of the Mikoyan Visit..., 1959 (Box 26)
    - Bessie, Alwah C. Soviet People at War..., undated (Box 26)
    - Harrington, Donald. Must We Eventually Fight the Soviet Union, undated (Box 26)
  - American-Soviet Friendship, 1931-1951
    - Friends of the Soviet Union. Soviet Pictorial: Forging Ahead, [1931?] [not an exact duplicate of previous pamphlet -- differences in copy] (Box 26)
    - Why Soviet Russia Should Be Recognized..., [1933?] (Box 26)
    - American Russian Institute. Are You Interested in Soviet Russia?... [1934?] (Box 26)
    - Heller, A. A. One Sixth of the World, [1937?] (Box 26)
    - Lamont, Corliss. The Story of Soviet Progress, 1938 (Box 26)
    - Johnson, Hewlitt. The Road to Peace, 1949 (Box 26)
    - Pepper, Claude. An American Policy for Peace: A Program for Big Three Unity and American-Soviet Friendship, [1950?] (Box 26)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship. Seeing Is Believing: Americans Go Visiting the Soviet Union, 1951 (Box 26)
    - Friends of the Soviet Union. 15 Years of the Soviet Union, undated (Box 26)
    - Soviet "Dumping" and "Forced Labor," undated (Box 26)
    - Soviet Pictorial: Forging Ahead, undated (Box 26)
    - Through Workers' Eyes: Report of the American Workers' Delegation to Soviet Russia, undated [use copy] (Box 26)
    - Who are the Friends of the Soviet Union? undated (Box 26)
    - Heller, A. A. One Hundred Years in Ten..., undated (Box 26)
    - Who Wants War?, undated (Box 26)
    - Kingsbury, John A. Soviet Impressions, undated (Box 26)
  - British-Soviet Friendship, 1945-1952
    Several purport to be eye-witness accounts from Russia, with two published by the British Workers' Delegation to the Soviet Union.
    - Litauer, Stefan. Poland's Case, 1945 (Box 27)
    - Clegg, Arthur. The U.S.S.R. and China, 1946 (Box 27)
    - Lewis, John. The Basis of Soviet Philosophy, 1947 (Box 27)
    - Evans, Stanley G. The U.S.S.R. and U.N., 1949 (Box 27)
    - Montagu, Ivor G. S. Joseph Stalin: Seventy Years, [1949?] (Box 27)
    - Scottish Area of the British National Union of Mineworkers' Delegation to the Soviet Union. Where Miners Are Honored..., 1950 (Box 27)
    - British Workers' Delegation to the Soviet Union. Russia with our Own Eyes..., 1951 (Box 27)
    - British Workers' Delegation to U.S.S.R. Russia, 1952: The Complete Report of 12 British Trade Unionists..., 1952 (Box 27)
- Radical Movements, U.S.A. and Canada -- Songs and Poetry, 1912-1950; 10 pamphlets
  Eight collections of songs, one of poetry by Wilfred Gribble, and one children's book in prose.
  - Gribble, Wilfred. Rhymes of Revolt, 1912 (Box 27)
  - Socialist Party, USA. Some Songs of Socialism, 1912 (Box 27)
  - Workers Music League. Red Song Book, 1932 (Box 27)
  - Songs of Struggle [bilingual], 1932 [use copy] (Box 27)
  - Redfield, A. Mr. His: A Children's Story for Anybody, 1939 (Box 27)
  - Robinson, Earl [comp.]. America Sings, [1939?] (Box 27)
  - America Sings, [193-?] (Box 27)
  - Jefferson, Bill. Songs for Peace, 1940 (Box 27)
  - Stevens, Alexander [comp.]. America Sings for Victory, [1941?] (Box 27)
  - Marks, Gerald and Milton Pascal. Sing a Labor Song, 1950 (Box 27)
- Preservation Originals
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original pamphlets in this series are restricted for preservation reasons. Use copies exist in the collections.
  Series contains original pamphlets removed from the main run of pamphlets and housed separately due to preservation concerns. Use copies of these originals are filed in the main pamphlet run and indicated with the use copy designation.
  - Originals removed for preservation (Box 28)
  - Originals removed for preservation (Box 29)